JESUS GASTAÑADUY FIESTAS

Lima, Peru

(+51) 985-801-090 | j.gastanaduy@pucp.pe | www.linkedin.com/in/j-gastanaduy/ | https://j-gastanaduy.github.io/

PROFESSIONAL SUMMARY

Thoughtful quantitative psychologist, with more than 3 years of experience designing and evaluating business experiments, as well as conducting quantitative and qualitative research for the private and public sector. Oriented to goal achievement; with high project management and analytical skills, in addition to effective communication. Interested in helping organizations make evidence-based decisions through the application of behavioral insights, causal inference and machine learning methods.

EDUCATION

PONTIFICIA UNIVERSIDAD CATÓLICA DEL PERÚ

LIMA, PERU

B.A. in Psychology

Mar 2014- Apr 2020

Magna Cum Laude | GPA: 17.19/20.00

Diploma in Data Science for the Social Sciences and Public Administration

Ago 2021- Jul 2022

• (In progress)

UNIVERSITY OF WISCONSIN-MADISON

WISCONSIN, UNITED STATES

Exchange Program

SEP 2018- DEC 2018

Earned CRS: 18 | GPA: 3.89/4.00

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

RIMAC SEGUROS Y REASEGUROS (INSURANCE COMPANY | https://www.rimac.com/)

LIMA, PERU

CX Metrics & Analytics Specialist

Mar 2022- Present

- Developed a statistical model that explained customer satisfaction and loyalty in over 60% using administrative data.
- Incentivised the development of initiatives aimed to foster and better understand "trust" in the financial sector, after identifying it as a main driver of customer satisfaction and loyalty through statistical analysis.

Behavioral Designer Oct 2021 – Feb 2022

• Defined the experimental methodology and impact evaluation for numerous service design initiatives, aimed to serve key strategic goals within the company.

HEURÍSTICA LAB (BEHAVIORAL SCIENCE CONSULTING FIRM | https://www.heuristicalab.com/)

LIMA, PERU

Behavioral Researcher

Apr 2020 - Oct 2021

- Consulting team member of two World Bank projects dedicated to improve early childhood in Peru and Brazil through the implementation of behavioral insights within National Program's "Cuna Más" and "Criança Feliz", which aid over 170K and 900k families under poverty.
- Project manager of two qualitative studies aimed to understand key psychological factors of financial behavior through behavioral insights for the largest consumer bank in Peru

Behavioral Science Intern

Aug 2019 - Mar 2020

- Co-created one of the selected proposals by the Inter-American Development Bank (IDB) to increase trust in Latin America and the Caribbean.
- Co-created and co-dictated an in-house training on "Design and Evaluation in Behavioral Science" to promote a culture of experimentation within the leading insurance company in Peru.

RESEARCH EXPERIENCE

CENTER FOR HEALTHY MINDS (RESEARCH LAB AT UW-MADISON | https://centerhealthyminds.org/)

Lima, Peru

Honorary fellow

JAN 2019 - DEC 2019

Supported quantitative and qualitative evaluations of socio-emotional education programs in Mexico.

Undergraduate student

SEP 2018 - DEC 2018

Supported research to provide mindfulness training for preschool principals in Mexico.

ACHIEVEMENTS

CERTIFICATIONS

Data Science Professional Certificate - HarvardX - 2020

CONFERENCES

Speaker at the ESA Online Special Meeting Buenos Aires — UChicago	FEB 2022
Speaker at the II International Congress of Economics, Banking and Finance – ULima	Nov 2019
Speaker at the International Seminar "Journey to the corrupt brain: Psychology, Neuroscience and Law"- PUCP	May 2019
Speaker at the Lima Conference on Experimental and Behavioural Economics (international event) - PUCP	JUL 2018

FUNDING

Awardee of the Academic Research Support Program - PUCP Gastañaduy (PI) APR 2019 - Aug 2020 Dishonesty in the presence of moral emotions: two experiments among undergraduate students and the public in general. Role: PI/Awardee | Funding Amount: € 1000

TECHNICAL SKILLS

R (advanced); Python(intermediate); SPSS (advanced); Microsoft Excel (intermediate); Qualtrics (intermediate)

OTHER INTERESTING INFORMATION

Meditation practitioner | Amateur guitar and piano player | Ex-gymnast